Diego Favero

Full Stack WebDeveloper (resume)

Samples: https://github.com/orisha/SampleCodesPHPJavaScriptGoLang

GitHub: https://github.com/orisha

StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/688689/diego-favero

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/faverodiego/

Brazilian 16th, May, 1981

diego.g.favero@gmail.com +55 75 998123412

Portuguese: Mother Tongue

English: Advanced Spanish: Intermediary Italian, French: Basic

Bachelor's degree in Information Systems.

@ São Paulo State University (UNESP)

Since 2003

| Most Used | | |
|---------------|---|--|
| BackEnd | PHP (Symfony Laravel) Golang | |
| FrontEnd | TypeScript SASS JavaScript ReactJS jQuery | |
| Agile | Jira Trello RunRun.it | |
| DevOps | Linux Docker circleCl sonarCloud | |
| DataBase | MySql MongoDB Postgres | |
| Mobile | Kotlin | |
| Techniques | Microservice API OOP Ajax TDD BDD EDD | |
| Want to Learn | Machine Learning Data Science DevOps Automation DevSecOps | |

| Formal Work Experience | |
|------------------------|---|
| <u>Alooba</u> | FullStack Software Engineer. My daily activities are basically to kill bugs on legacy app and develop new features on the v2 app. Besides the coding, I also have to: Test and/or Code review other co-workers tasks. |
| NetSar | Senior PHP Programmer. I was leading a small team (me plus 2 programmers, occasionally a designer) responsible for re-write the old scripts into a new Symfony based platform. Eventually, I did write codes for new features. Most of the system was based on SOAP/REST . |

I am multitasking with vast tech knowledge: I can fit in many positions in the IT team.

My interests go through UI/UX, AR, Machine Learning, Data Science and other. Keep scrolling to see my full Curriculum.

Diego Favero Full Stack WebDeveloper (full CV)

Online Resume and Code Samples: http://18.216.194.20/diegofavero.dev/

GitHub: https://github.com/orisha

StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/688689/diego-favero

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/faverodiego/

Brazilian, Born at: 16th, May, 1981 E-mail: diego.g.favero@gmail.com Phone: +55 75 998123412

Common Used Tools

#PHP #MYSQL #GOLANG

#REACT #LINUX #JAVASCRIPT

#SYMFONY #TYPESCRIPT #DOCKER

About me:

I have been using **PHP** and its 'sidekicks' for web development since **1999** when I started to be an intern in the university's computer's lab.

Today I am able to work in any stage from a system development:

Since analyzing system requirements, going through server setup, database design and administration, team managing, coding (Structure, **Backend** and Frontend), test and deployment!

Currently, I have based my personal projects on **microservice** architecture. Using **Golang** as BackEnd .

I am really up to start to learn new technologies.

Today, I consider myself a better fit as a **backend developer** than frontend.

I Have a good knowledge about Photography, Video Editing and Audio Production, able to use many softwares such as Adobe suite, Logic Pro, Ableton Live and many others. I have been DJing since 2007.

As a hobby I like outdoor sports such as rock climbing, trekking and mountain biking, and sometimes, I make awesome woodwork! (Most of my house's furniture is made by me).

Technical Skills

Level 8 (I would be able to perform a workshop of these right now)

PHP OOP Mysql

Level 7 (I can work very well using these, with some kind of expertise)

Javascript Jquery Symfony PHPStorm (IDE) OSX Linux

Level 6 (I Can do it! Maybe I'll use google to check any syntax or a forgotten detail)

GoLang API **TypeScript** Mysql Server Git **AWS** SOAP/REST SEO DBA TDD Kotlin Docker React Nginx BDD SASS/LESS CSS3 HTML5

Level 5 (I can do it! I have already used it! Just give a few days on google)

XML Vue .js Design Patterns Node.js Angular SSL / HTTPS

Level 4 (tools I already used, but not that much, so I am able to use it)

ExtJS Kendo UI Codelgniter

Level 3 (I know what is and how to apply, but never worked using those before)

Ruby NoSql WordPress Bootstrap Pearl Kubernetes

Level 2 (Languages I learned in college, but never used professionally)

C, C++ Java Pascal Cobol Lua Delphi Assemble Fortran ASP

Education:

Title: Bachelor

Course: Information Systems Bachelor's Degree at **UNESP** (Sao Paulo State University) from March 1999 until December 2003

The Course, basically, is a shortened form of Science Computers **plus** company management course. In short words: **It teaches how to apply computers based systems for companies**.

- * Original title in portuguese : Bacharelado em Sistemas de Informação.
- ** The <u>Information Systems Bachelor</u> at UNESP is the first course of its kind in Brazil. And since them it has been always ranked as #1 in Brazil.
- ***The Sao Paulo State University is in the top 4 Brazilian Ranking and it is in the top 400 world wide.

Languages Skills

Portuguese (pt-BR): native speaker.

English: Advanced

I (really) learned English when was **living** in Amsterdam (2008-2009), today I could say that I am aware of my strong Brazilian accent, also a few mess when need to use 'in', 'on', 'at', etc, although, I think I can **express** myself clearly enough to hold any kind of conversation, written or **spoken**.

Spanish: Intermediary

Due to its **similarity** to portuguese, I can understand spanish very well when spoken and fully when read . But I can not speak as good as I speak English

French/Italian: Self Learning

Like Spanish, these other **latin** languages are kind of easy to understand, but I still don't get much of it when spoken. I just need a bit more practice.

Work Experience

__<u>Alooba</u> FullStack Software Engineer Jul 2020 — Current Australian Based Company - Home Office.

It is a startup company from Australia which recently got a substantial investment. It provides **solutions** for hiring processes focused on Data Sciences roles.

My function is to maintain the current software and develop new features. Using Laravel, PHP, Postgres and React/TypeScript.

NetSar Senior PHP Programmer nov 2012 — Jul 2014

Brazilian Based Company - Home Office

It is a medium software company in Brazil providing **solutions** for travel shop's. It was a home based job. I was **leading** a small team (me plus 2 programmers, occasionally a designer) responsible for re-write the old scripts into a new **Symfony** based platform . Eventually, I did write codes for new features . Most of the system was based on **SOAP/REST** servers!

Reason for getting off: In may 2014 I had a motorcycle crash, which costs me three broken ribs, a pierced lung, a week in the hospital and almost my life. After that I decided to give myself some time so I asked to get off for travel.

<u>Advosoft</u> PHP Developer Jun 2012 — Oct 2012 USA Based company. - Home Office

It was a home based job. I was simply coding new **features** according to the projects previously sent through some collab tool .

Reason for getting off: They let me go without further explanation.

<u>Ecentry</u> Jr PHP Developer - Jan 2010 — Dec 2011 Brazil Based Company - Office Based Job

I Was working on a Fidelity Program System owned by **Lufthansa** Flight Company. This system is responsible for managing the Fidelity Points Program for the ones who sell Lufthansa tickets. It was a huge system within almost **2M** users, translated into more than 80 **languages**.

I had two main **functions**:

- 1 **Maintenance**: Had to quickly fix any reported bug.
- 2 New Interface and Database **Optimization**: While no bugs were reported, I had a mission to check and optimize the **SQL's** query and system performance. To do so, I was migrating all queries to be executed by **Python** Scripts.

The new interface was developed using **ExtJS** Framework.

Reason to get off: I was sick of having to spend two hours every day into the Brazilian mad traffic. After being denied to work home based, I asked to quit!

My Goals

| _ MultiTask and vast tech knowledge: I can fit in many positions in the IT department. |
|---|
| _ Can travel or move in anytime . |
| _ Dare me on new challenges ! |
| _ I think 'out the box' and love to learn. |
| _ I can inject new market vision ('cause I live the Brazilian reality, would be a nice info and |
| experiences exchange about this huge and growing marketing we have around here). |

Interests

Augmented Reality UI / UX New Technologies

Qubits Data Security Networks

Big Data Machine Learning IA

Interests beyond IT

| Disate / Vide a / Audia Dasdustian and Edition |
|--|
| _ Photo / Video / Audio Production and Edition |
| _ Sports -> Climbing, Mountain bike, Surf, SlackLine and Trekking. |
| _ Healthier life and food . |
| _ Travel |
| _ Quantum physics. |
| _ Yoga and Capoeira . |
| _ Politics and Economy . |
| _ Dogs . |
| _ Simple Life . |

A few things I like to do and learn about in my spare time :

Why hire me?

_ Carpenter and Architecture .

Because I have a full **domain** about how to attend to the job needs (if hooded by my **skills**, otherwise, I am fully open to learn it) with a few pluses acquired by life experience. And, I have a passion for working with **technologies**!

Want to see more?

Please, ask for a code sample and I will be glad to send a few files with pieces of code I've written